interface idiomObj {
	idiom: string;
	definition: string;
	question: string;
	a: string;
	b: string;
	c: string;
	d: string;
	correct: string;
}

export const idioms: idiomObj[] = [
	{
		idiom: 'To cost an arm and a leg',
		definition: 'To be very expensive.',
		question:
			'That dimond ring from Tiffani cost me an arm and a   _____  .',
		a: 'leg',
		b: 'hand',
		c: 'finger',
		d: 'shoulder',
		correct: 'leg',
	},
	{
		idiom: "To keep (someone or something) at arm's length",
		definition:
			'To avoid being very close or friendly with someone or something.',
		question:
			'They no longer trust her and are keeping her at  _____  length.',
		a: "hand's",
		b: "head's",
		c: "arm's",
		d: "body's",
		correct: "arm's",
	},
	{
		idiom: "To get something off one's chest",
		definition: 'To tell someone your problems or frustrations.',
		question:
			'Thanks for letting me share my problem with you! I needed to get it off my  _____  .',
		a: 'skin',
		b: 'head',
		c: 'heart',
		d: 'chest',
		correct: 'chest',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'A sweet tooth',
		definition: 'A strong liking for sugary foods.',
		question:
			'She has a real sweet  _____  for various deserts and sweet drinks.',
		a: 'tooth',
		b: 'bone',
		c: 'mouth',
		d: 'tongue',
		correct: 'tooth',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To be all ears',
		definition: 'To be eager to listen very attentively.',
		question:
			"So, did Mike propose to you yesterday? Come on, I'm all  _____  !",
		a: 'hair',
		b: 'ears',
		c: 'skin',
		d: 'heart',
		correct: 'ears',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To give/show someone the cold shoulder',
		definition: 'To ignore someone.',
		question:
			'When I said hello to her in the library, she gave me the cold  _____  and walked away.',
		a: 'eye',
		b: 'shoulder',
		c: 'heart',
		d: 'hand',
		correct: 'shoulder',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To keep your chin up',
		definition: 'To try to stay positive when things seem negative.',
		question:
			'Come on, failing a school exam is not the end of the world — keep your  _____  up!',
		a: 'eyes',
		b: 'shoulder',
		c: 'nose',
		d: 'chin',
		correct: 'chin',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To have itchy feet',
		definition: 'To want to go somewhere new or start doing something new.',
		question:
			'Every so often, Claire has itchy  _____  and sets off for a foreign destination.',
		a: 'tongue',
		b: 'head',
		c: 'leg',
		d: 'feet',
		correct: 'feet',
	},
	{
		idiom: "To put one's foot in one's mouth",
		definition:
			'To say or do something that accidentally embarrasses or offends another person.',
		question:
			"I put my  _____  in my mouth when I called by brother's new wife by his ex-wife's name.",
		a: 'hand',
		b: 'foot',
		c: 'head',
		d: 'finger',
		correct: 'foot',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To play it by ear',
		definition: 'To improvise or do something without preparation',
		question:
			"I don't know where we should go tonight. Let's just play it by  _____  .",
		a: 'heart',
		b: 'spine',
		c: 'teeth',
		d: 'ear',
		correct: 'ear',
	},
	{
		idiom: "To pull one's leg",
		definition: 'To joke or tease someone.',
		question:
			"I was just pulling your  _____  . I'm not really a police officer.",
		a: 'leg',
		b: 'finger',
		c: 'hair',
		d: 'hand',
		correct: 'leg',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To see eye to eye (with somebody about/on/over something)',
		definition: 'To agree completely.',
		question:
			'They have never been able to see eye to  _____   on politics.',
		a: 'head',
		b: 'skin',
		c: 'eye',
		d: 'shoulder',
		correct: 'eye',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To be all thumbs',
		definition: 'To be clumsy.',
		question:
			'You have dropped your phone three times today! You are all  _____  !',
		a: 'hands',
		b: 'eyes',
		c: 'ears',
		d: 'thumbs',
		correct: 'thumbs',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'Break a leg!',
		definition:
			'Used for wishing someone good luck, especially before a performance',
		question: 'Hope you break a  _____  at your job interview tomorrow.',
		a: 'leg',
		b: 'back',
		c: 'head',
		d: 'finger',
		correct: 'leg',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To have a finger in every/many pie(s)',
		definition: 'To be involved in a lot of different activities.',
		question:
			"Monica wouldn't be so busy and stressed if she didn't have a  _____   in every pie.",
		a: 'toe',
		b: 'hand',
		c: 'finger',
		d: 'nose',
		correct: 'finger',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To pay through the nose',
		definition: 'To pay more for something than is fair or reasonable',
		question:
			"You can get pretty good meals on airplanes these days, but you're going to pay through the  _____  .",
		a: 'nose',
		b: 'spine',
		c: 'tongue',
		d: 'head',
		correct: 'nose',
	},
	{
		idiom: "To be/get in over one's head",
		definition:
			"to be stuck in a difficult situation that you don't have the ability or resources to escape.",
		question:
			'It was only after he’d started to borrow money from the local mafia that he realized he was in over his  _____  .',
		a: 'leg',
		b: 'head',
		c: 'hair',
		d: 'stomach',
		correct: 'head',
	},
	{
		idiom: "To let one's hair down",
		definition: 'To relax completely and enjoy yourself.',
		question:
			'Come on, Jim, this is a party! Let your  _____  down and go a little wild!',
		a: 'hair',
		b: 'finger',
		c: 'hand',
		d: 'knuckle',
		correct: 'hair',
	},
	{
		idiom: "To pick one's brain",
		definition:
			'To talk with someone to find out information about something.',
		question:
			"You should pick John's  _____  sometime. He knows all about car engines.",
		a: 'back',
		b: 'brain',
		c: 'head',
		d: 'mouth',
		correct: 'brain',
	},
	{
		idiom: 'To pay lip service',
		definition:
			'To express loyalty, respect, or support for something insincerely',
		question:
			'Most of our politicians do nothing but pay  _____  service to the major issues affecting our country.',
		a: 'mouth',
		b: 'eye',
		c: 'tongue',
		d: 'lip',
		correct: 'lip',
	},
];
